Hello we're the post-quantum cryptography
group and this is our senior capstone design
project. So as a quick road map, we are
going to be going into: the motivation,
the implementation, a quick demo of our project,
and as well as a quick evaluation of our solution.
And here's the motivation. So, cryptography
is a form of communicating securely between
multiple entities, and the three things that
it gives you is: confidentiality, integrity,
and authenticity. And in our project, we want
to explain two term terms-- classical and
post-quantum cryptography. Currently, computers
use classical and we're trying to prove the
viability of post-quantum. Now, with the rise of
quantum computers, the current encryption schemes,
classical, are crackable and need to be brought
up to speed. Our solution is to make post-quantum
encryption algorithms available and easy to
use. Currently we've created a quantum-safe
network application and measured its performance
for an open-source release. So, quickly going into
the implementation of our project, the tech
stack that we mainly used was mainly: Go,
Bash, and Python. And so um, for our project
we created a library called qs509 and as you
can see in the code here, we are importing our
library to be used, and this Library provides
the post-quantum functionality. And so here's
a quick overview of how the client and server
kind of interact with our library. Uh the main
things to note are that both the client and server
create certificates and they send it across to
each other and they verify to create the secure
environment. For the Mininet simulations, in this
image you can see geosynchronous satellites at
the top, lower satellites at the bottom, and
terrestrial networks, such as New York to LA
and New York to Tokyo, at the bottom. Going into
a quick demo, we can see how our system works. We
are launching a Mininet topology here with two
hosts, H1 and H2. H1 is hosting the server and
H2 is a client connecting and communicating
with the server. We launch the server and it
starts listening to see if there's any clients
that want to talk to it. When a client connects,
we can see a lot of information is dumped out--
like a certificate being created and exchanged
and a password being shared that allows them
to encrypt and decrypt messages as shown
there. Moving on to the evaluation, we used three
crucial steps, this was: unit and integration
testing, UAT, and then comparing our results to
the theory. For unit testing, we tested every
function individually to make sure every possible
execution path worked. And then for integration
testing, we made sure to test that all the
components that we had work together correctly.
We put our project back into the hands of the
sponsors and got a lot of positive feedback,
with a unanimous agreement that we completed all
the required aspects of this project. Looking
at our results, we can see that post-quantum
cryptography is very viable in regular network
topologies as long as there's no high packet
loss or low bandwidth. Thanks and gig'em!